No entry
Tsubasa Family     Part Two
A bite
Two bites
Three bites
Ate it in three bites
French Cruller
Napkin
On the ground
Time passes
Araragi  Tsukihi
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Help
That's what he said.
You  endured  well  until  now.
Thank  you.
Now on to the main topic.
Curse  Cat
A lone home call
Child's Play
Underage  Privilege
Out of bounds
Hanekawa Tsubasa
A girl with otherworldly wings
Switch on
Curse
Caress
calls
msgs
Zenmonogatari green-lit!
It's us! The Fire Sisters!
I'll grant all of                                  my master's wishes!
List
Ah! That's the cat
from New Year's Eve!
Catch it!
You got caught in my trap!
Fire Sisters!
A pitfall...
The last one is to take over the preview!
Just sit there quietly and watch!
Next Episode
Tsubasa  Family      Part  Three
She took over before I could!