Scene no. 1
No entry
You don't have to glare like that.
It ruins your beautiful face.
Come on, give me a smile.
That's what suits you best.
You could at least act like you appreciate it.
Huh?
Uh...
Inside the darkness
my love softly blossomed
like a flower for the first time
I'm sure you don't realize it
Tsubasa Family     Part Two
You held out your hand to me
and although I found no strength to take it
I want you to hold it out to me
for just a while longer
That is my ray of light in the darkness
I don't want to know the future
of my love just yet
30th  April
Hold on... Are you serious?
Sure, she might be a dried up husk,
a mere shadow of her former self,
but this is still a proud vampire we're talking about here.
And there's no way she'd be finding donuts irresistible instead of what's in front of her.
Quit disillusioning me!
A-Are you okay?
Oh, right.
Donuts
Scene no. 52
Golden chocolate
Scene no. 53
A bite
Scene no. 56
Two bites
Scene no. 57
Three bites
Scene no. 58
Ate it in three bites
Not so fast!
Sit!
Purple
Unnumbered scene
French Cruller
Scene no. 67
Napkin
On the ground
Scene no. 67
Paw.
Good. Now eat.
I-I got these for Oshino, you know...
I get the feeling I'm being pressured here.
Time passes
Scene no. 74
Though, well, it could be my guilt that's threatening to crush me under its weight right now.
Because I'm the reason this little vampire's been forced into a lifestyle like this.
Ever since spring break, she hasn't said a thing.
She frequently had a smile on her face back then, but all she wears now is a sour, sullen expression.
I'm fully aware that I shouldn't feel any compassion for her, not even the bare minimum as a human,
considering what she did and what she's done all her life, but...
All right, fine.
I'll let you have them all.
You'll have to do a 1080 and bark like a dog, though.
So she still won't talk, huh?
Eat.
Wonderful! These circular snacks are seriously scrumptious!
This is truly a jewelry box of sweet, sweet rings.
Did you just speak?!
So I was just hearing things...
The heck are you doing, Araragi-kun?
You shouldn't bully Vampire-chan too much.
It might come back to bite you.
I'm not bullying her.
More importantly, this has been bothering me ever since spring break.
Hasn't she become a lot more childish mentally as well?
Yeah. That was bound to happen, Araragi-kun.
And not just because she's a vampire, either.
Oddities are creatures built from the ground up by human beliefs.
Human beliefs?
Right. They exist because humans believe they do.
That's what an oddity is.
They're shaped by their environment's awareness of them,
and their behavior matches its expectations.
That's how it works.
Now then, as for Vampire-chan here...
At the moment, you're the only entity aware of her existence.
Strictly speaking, I suppose both
Ms. Class Rep and I are also aware.
Nevertheless, the one that exerts the most influence on her
is you.
I have to admit that there's a part of me that sees her as an eight-year-old.
Still,
you can't possibly tell me this is what I expect from her.
It's not like every kid grows up the way their parents would like them to.
However, the hopes of their parents affect them at least a little.
It's a bit like that.
A parent's hopes...
The effect of one's household...
I'm not gonna preach to you about how you should become a better human being,
but screw around too much and your influence could end up becoming a negative one.
Considering...
Considering I've already brought that proud vampire down to this innocent child-like state,
the least I could do is not make things worse for her.
That's what it boils down to.
Black
Unnumbered scene
That aside, Araragi-kun.
I brought her up earlier, so I guess I might as well ask. How's Ms. Class Rep doing?
What do you mean? She's fine.
Really?
I see. You can't say.
Which means...
Something happened to her that you can't talk to me about.
That worries me.
It's not something to concern yourself with.
It's Hanekawa's problem to deal with,
so I can't be too meddlesome.
Even if something did happen, she'd have to save herself.
If not, she'd be beyond help. Right?
Hmm, I see. I won't press you any further, then.
Let's look at it the other way around.
Tell me what you can.
It's not like you're forbidden from ever saying anything about her, right?
Flashback
Scene no. 166
I told him about today's events while cleverly—or maybe not
so cleverly—omitting the things I was forbidden from saying.
Araragi  Tsukihi
Scene no. 167
Starting from this morning,
when I was woken up by my little sister,
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Scene no. 170
up to my chance encounter with Hanekawa.
And lastly, what happened afterwards.
Time passes
Scene no. 172
Help
Scene no. 181
End  of  flashback
Scene no. 182
Araragi-kun, please don't tell me...
that it was a silver cat without a tail.
That's what he said.
Scene no. 218
Black
Unnumbered scene
You  endured  well  until  now.
Scene no. 219
Thank  you.
Now on to the main topic.
Scene no. 219
Scene no. 220
The Curse Cat.
Curse  Cat
Scene no. 225
Order Carnivora. Family Felidae. Mammal.
It's one of the oddity tales I'm collecting in this town.
Hold on a second, Oshino.
The cat Hanekawa and I buried wasn't an oddity.
It couldn't be. It actually existed.
Yeah, it couldn't possibly be one.
That's what I'd think too...
Under normal circumstances.
However, Araragi-kun. Ms. Class Rep is anything but normal.
She's seriously dangerous.
Burying a cat that was run over is a trivial, commonplace occurrence.
You could even call it heartwarming.
Even something that simple could become an earth-shattering incident just because she's involved.
The fact that it was a cat makes things even worse.
Hmm?
The Curse Cat is way too perfect a fit for Ms. Class Rep.
What should I do then, Oshino?
The fastest way to do things here would be to split up.
I'll go exhume the white cat you buried.
So all I need to do is tell you where we buried it?
In return, I'll have you shoulder a different, more important responsibility.
Huh?
Like I said, we'll split up.
I'll have you contact Ms. Class Rep directly.
D-Directly?
You're going to visit her place,
lay eyes on her, and confirm she's safe.
Talk to her,
and pay close attention to her eyes when you do.
A lone home call
Good grief. This has spiraled out of control.
Actually, how am I even supposed to meet Hanekawa at this hour?
Child's Play
Underage  Privilege
Out of bounds
Hanekawa?
Huh? But wait...
Is that Hanekawa?
Meow!
Meow.
Ha-Hanekawa...
Who're you? A friend of my master's, purrhaps?
Come to think of it, I do get the impurrsion I've seen you before.
You're the dude who was with her when she buried me, aren't you?
Purrfect timing.
I'm not sure I fully understand, but friends are supposed to help each other out, right?
So clean this mess up fur her, yeah?
Red
Unnumbered scene
Er, what would you call it meow?
Oh, right.
Those are appurrently my master's parents.
I'm not sure, though.
Feel free to dispose of them using any method you purrfer.
If you want to,
you can even kill them, fur all I care.
Hey! Wait a second, Hanekawa!
Wait for what?
Don't just keep burdening my master with all of your hopes and expectations, fool!
She's in this state because you're all like that!
Red
Unnumbered scene
Ow!
Don't make such a fuss over something like this.
Compared to the agony my master's endured fur such a long time,
the amount of pain you're in now is nothing!
By master...
Does she mean Hanekawa?
Yeah. That's right, human.
She has me meow, so she doesn't need you anymore.
She doesn't need parents, friends,
or even herself.
None of it.
What?
I'll set my master free. Grant her lipurrty far surpassing anyone else.
The lot of you couldn't do that fur her, you know.
All you could do was chain her down and cause problems fur her.
Red
Unnumbered scene
Furst things furst,
I'll release her from the enormous stress she's under.
Hanekawa...
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Scene no. 373
A girl with otherworldly wings
Scene no. 374
Scene no. 387
Switch on
The first thing I did after the Curse Cat left was sort out the chaotic state of affairs.
I called for an ambulance.
As for that residential area street I covered in a pool of my own blood,
I'd normally need a deck brush and a whole lot of water to clean up that mess.
However, my blood had started evaporating without me having to do a thing.
Of course, I didn't find that strange at all. It was
something I'd grown tired of seeing during spring break.
Black
Unnumbered scene
What I should've found strange though, was that my blood was taking much longer than usual to evaporate.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Wh-Whoa!
You awake, Araragi-kun?
Quite the sleepyhead, aren't we?
I got tired of waiting.
Look, it's almost sunset.
I was asleep for more than twelve hours?
I thought you were gonna die.
Hey, Oshino! Hanekawa's—
Yeah, I know.
I heard about it already.
Our little class rep's turned into a cat, right?
Looks like our worst fears came true.
You can go now, Vampire-chan.
What was that all about?
Why was she even awake at this hour?
Well, your injuries were much too severe,
so I had her help out a little.
Take a look.
The two of you have a really strong link,
and the same goes for your healing abilities as well.
They're more effective the closer you are to each other.
Make sure you thank her later.
I was really surprised, though.
I thought I'd heal much more quickly given that she drank my blood not long before it happened.
Nah. Your immortality should currently be able to take care of most serious injuries.
Everything but a fatal wound should heal in an instant.
In this case, though,
you just picked the wrong opponent.
Well, it has less to do with your opponent and more with the matchup.
It was a bad matchup.
The Curse Cat is bad news.
B-Bad news?
There's more to the wounds inflicted by its curse,
its caress, than the damage it causes you.
Curse
Caress
As they say, it's best to let sleeping cats lie. Don't touch them.
Araragi-kun, are you familiar with the concept of an Energy Drain?
Energy Drain?
Wait, isn't that supposed to be a vampire's specialty?
That's exactly right.
However, that doesn't mean it's exclusive to vampires.
So what you're trying to say, basically, is that my immortality got torn off along with my left arm?
You're done for if you let the Curse Cat caress you.
That's why it's named the Curse Cat, huh?
Either way, an Energy Drain that overpowers a vampire's immortality is quite the threat.
Not really, no.
Maybe I worded it wrong, Araragi-kun.
When I said matchup, I meant how it matched up with you personally.
I didn't mean to say the Curse Cat was as strong as a vampire.
Huh?
Vampires are the kings of oddities.
Emperors. Monarchs.
The Curse Cat might have the ability to use Energy Drain, but not one nearly as powerful.
To a vampire, the Curse Cat is just a weakling.
Weakling?
Not much time had passed since you let Vampire-chan drink your blood,
so you probably were, to some degree, a vampire at the time.
But at the end of the day? You're human.
You don't stand a chance against a real oddity.
A real oddity...
I tried digging up that grave you told me about, but I didn't find anything buried.
This is pretty much the worst-case scenario.
I see.
That said, your wound appears to be healing well.
Doesn't look like it's been fully attached on the inside, but you should be fine by tomorrow at this rate.
Vampire-chan... is probably asleep by now, so you better thank her next time.
Well, it's quite obvious that she'd gladly attend to you for one afternoon,
considering it'd cause her huge problems if you died.
That's something I'm happy to hear, though.
That she needs me as a source of nutrition proves that she is,
at the very least, trying to stay alive.
That's not really what I meant, though.
You thickheaded idiot.
Huh?
Anyway, Araragi-kun. Go home before your family starts to worry.
The cellphone in your pocket was shaking like crazy.
What's the word, vibrating?
calls
msgs
They're probably all from Karen and Tsukihi.
Unlike Ms. Class Rep, you have a family that'd worry about you,
so you'd better go home now, Araragi-kun.
Enough, Oshino.
This injury doesn't change anything.
I can't just run along home when Hanekawa's in that state.
It's far too late for that.
Time to leave it to the pros.
Not to an amateur, and definitely not to a minor.
It might not be obvious due to my frivolous nature,
but I really am sorry I got you so badly injured.
I'm a failure as a balancer.
I disregarded the textbook course of action and did something that went against my policy.
My lapse in judgment was the main reason you got put in harm's way.
I can't apologize enough to your family.
You've done more than enough, Araragi-kun.
Araragi Koyomi-kun,
there isn't a single thing you can do from here on out.
You can't help Ms. Class Rep in any way whatsoever.
No matter how much you'd like to.
It's not a question of passion,
but one of skill and ability.
Let me make it absolutely clear.
It's your responsibility, and your job,
to make sure you don't get in my way.
And in spite of that we
laugh knowingly as though we
planned it beforehand
Sigh if you want to
and take a deep breath then
Don't worry if it looks foolish
I will keep waiting
for what you wish for
Would it be a lie to say
that there is still time?
I don't want to be saved
I don't want to be rewarded
I just want to enjoy these fragile days
Every day I make my wishes
My experiences remain bittersweet
Far atop the horizon I felt
my fading daydream
Preview
Script: Nisio Isin
Illustrations: Haritama Hiroki
This is a preview hallucination.
Preview
Zenmonogatari green-lit!
It's us! The Fire Sisters!
There exists a bodily response called "feigning death."
Preview
I'll grant all of                                  my master's wishes!
List
It's written not with the characters for "fake death," but with those for "pseudo-death."
Acting like you're dead, in other words.
Preview
Ah! That's the cat
from New Year's Eve!
Catch it!
Apparently, insects exhibit this behavior when they're on the verge of being crushed.
Preview
You got caught in my trap!
Fire Sisters!
A pitfall...
I suppose it's similar to how humans act like they're dead when they run into a bear.
Preview
The last one is to take over the preview!
Just sit there quietly and watch!
Wait, what's the point of doing that?!
Next Episode: Tsubasa Family Part Three.
Preview
Next Episode
Tsubasa  Family      Part  Three
Running into an oddity would be the opening act of death.
Preview
She took over before I could!