Scene no. 1
3rd  May
As for how I spent the rest of my Golden Week...
4th May
5th May
6th May
7th May
Well,
I spent it constantly kowtowing.
Inside the darkness
my love softly blossomed
like a flower for the first time
I'm sure you don't realize it
Tsubasa Family     Part Four
You held out your hand to me
and although I found no strength to take it
I want you to hold it out to me
for just a while longer
That is my ray of light in the darkness
I don't want to know the future
of my love just yet
Red
Unnumbered scene
The Demon Sword, "Heart Span,"
also known as the "Oddity Slayer."
So you got your hands on Heart Span?
That's great.
I'm really surprised that Vampire-chan changed her mind.
Let me congratulate you.
Ms. Class Rep's parents...
They've already been discharged from the hospital.
Really?
So I went and spoke to them for a bit.
I didn't get any information that'd prove useful in a fight against the Curse Cat,
but I did manage to hear one rather interesting anecdote.
An interesting anecdote?
About the time Ms. Class Rep's father hit her in the face.
He snapped and hit her really hard.
The blow apparently sent Ms. Class Rep flying all the way to the wall.
Well, she is pretty lightweight.
After she slammed into the wall and spent a little while squirming in pain,
what do you think Ms. Class Rep did next, Araragi-kun?
"You shouldn't hit a girl in the face, Dad."
That's what she said, apparently. With a smile on her face.
That's what she said after her father hit her?!
That?!
Creepy, isn't it?
She's so righteous it's scary.
Periwinkle
Unnumbered scene
She's terrifying. Even more terrifying than an oddity.
Revolting.
What, are you taking their side on this, Oshino?
I'm not going to take sides. I'm neutral.
I'm talking about standpoints here, that's all.
Ms. Class Rep has her point of view,
and her parents have their own.
There's no way for an outsider to know which of them is right.
Actually, there isn't a right one in the first place.
It's just about who's easier to agree with.
Still, Hanekawa's...
Hanekawa's in the right.
That's exactly what makes it so creepy and terrifying, right?
Of course, Ms. Class Rep's parents aren't exactly admirable people.
But you know, Araragi-kun,
I can't help but understand how they feel.
Just imagine living under the same roof with a person that righteous,
let alone your own daughter.
It sends shivers down my spine.
They had to live with someone so unbearably righteous for more than a dozen whole years.
Hanekawa
Tsubasa
In other words, they were trapped in a hell
where they had their ugliness and their immaturity shoved into their faces every single day. An absolute nightmare.
If anything, I almost admire that they lasted all those years without hitting her.
But no matter how you look at it,
there's no way that was Hanekawa's fault.
Oh, but it was.
Those with power must, at all times,
be aware of the effect their power has on those around them.
Curse
Scene no. 127
Curse everything she caressed
Curse everyone she caressed
Scene no. 127
As if flowers around her
curses bloomed
Scene no. 127
Everything about this current situation is irregular.
Anything and everything about it is irregular,
but Ms. Class Rep's the only irregularity.
Each and every single little thing
is Ms. Class Rep's fault.
I'm sorry, Oshino,
but could you stop badmouthing Hanekawa?
It makes me want to kill you.
Red
Unnumbered scene
Do you feel that way out of pity for Ms. Class Rep?
Hell no!
You're completely wrong.
It's not like you to be so ridiculously far off the mark, Oshino.
As if I'd ever feel any pity for her.
In fact, unlucky women only turn me on.
All I want is to relieve some of my sexual frustration.
It's just that this high school girl with cat ears, wearing only her underwear,
is driving me crazy with lust.
Scene no. 155
The Demon Sword, "Heart Span,"
is a lethal weapon that exists solely to slay oddities.
Using this Oddity Slayer will let me exterminate only the Curse Cat
without injuring Hanekawa in any way whatsoever.
I don't have anything else to say as a specialist,
but as your friend—
as your best friend—I want to warn you about a few things.
Warn me? About what?
Firstly.
That sword makes it possible to separate Ms. Class Rep from the Curse Cat.
That does indeed seem to be the best idea for dealing with the Curse Cat once and for all.
However, it's precisely because it seems like the best idea
that it will likely be the one thing
Ms. Class Rep is most on her guard against.
I mean, it's an idea that even you were able to think of,
Scene no. 162
so don't you think it would've been the first thing she anticipated and took measures against?
Might be
Scene no. 163
If we're talking hypothetically, yes.
However, I'm pretty confident that things will go smoothly.
I have a plan of my own.
A plan?
Well, maybe not a plan.
It's more of a hope.
You could call it my wishful thinking.
Scene no. 166
Hmm?
Okay. I'll just trust you on that one, then.
If you're really okay with that, that is.
I am. Don't make it sound like there's more to it.
What were the two other things you wanted to warn me about?
Actually, scratch the second one.
There's no point in even mentioning it.
Let me just go straight to the third.
At the time, I had a pretty good idea what Oshino's second warning would've been.
Here we go with the third and final warning.
A very important and practical question that needs to be asked, Araragi-kun.
How are you even going to find Ms. Class Rep?
She could be hiding anywhere in town.
I hope you don't expect me to help
Scene no. 174
Rest assured,
I have a proper plan for that.
One that's more than hopes or wishful thinking,
so you don't need to bother.
Anyway, let's each do our own thing from here on out.
As a specialist, you go look for the Curse Cat using your methods,
and I'll go look for it using mine.
Your methods, eh, Araragi-kun?
Yeah. Something you can't do.
My ultimate technique.
Oh?
Show me what you've got, then.
Do as you please.
I don't care if you end up causing a bloodbath or a tragedy.
Black
Unnumbered scene
No matter what happens, I won't interfere.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Send
White
Unnumbered scene
Are you all right, Araragi-kun?
Oh, I see.
You tricked me.
Yeah, I did.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Help me
A vampire's going to kill me... Help me!
Scene no. 199
Didn't take you long, Curse Cat.
Showing up in just thirty minutes?
You amaze me.
You're the worst, Araragi-kun.
Lying to people and making them worry
is not a very nice thing to do.
Hah!
What?
What's so funny? I'm really mad, you know.
Well, you see...
it's just that you've dropped that speech quirk of yours,
Hanekawa.
What's wrong, Ms. Honor Student?
Isn't the Curse Cat supposed to make cat puns all the time?
Wow.
White
Unnumbered scene
No, maybe I should say "meow" instead.
Either way—
Huh, what? When did you figure it out?
I just knew somehow. Right from the start.
I'm your friend, you know.
There's no way I'd mistake you for someone else.
And there's absolutely no way I wouldn't know it was you.
Regardless of whether you get possessed by an oddity, or take one in,
you'll always be the same, Hanekawa.
Your personality might change, but your character won't.
That's what you're like.
That's what makes you you.
If you got a text from a friend in trouble,
you'd rush to help them without a second thought,
regardless of the circumstances or the situation.
Like a cat instinctively spitting out furballs,
you'd rush to their aid without thinking.
That's who you are.
This?
This is who I am?
It is.
I mean, on one hand you're mad at me right now for lying to you,
but you're also feeling relieved, right?
You heaved a huge sigh of relief, didn't you?
You're incredibly kind and unbelievably strong.
Too kind and strong for your own good.
So overly kind that it drags the rest of your life down,
and so overly strong that you'd sell your soul to an oddity.
You're righteous enough to overwhelm people.
I understand why you'd want to deny that you are.
I don't understand, but at the same time, I do understand.
But you see, Hanekawa...
But you know, Hanekawa...
But Hanekawa...
That is who you are!
You're going to be that person for the rest of your life!
You are not going to change!
That's what you were born as, and that's what you've grown into, so just give it up!
You're going to have to just suck it up and live with yourself!
Listen to yourself, Araragi-kun.
Don't be so unreasonable.
It's hard on me too, you know.
Even I have things I can and cannot do.
I'm just a human too.
But you aren't.
Oddity
Scene no. 238
You gave yourself up to an oddity.
As you are now, you don't deserve to call yourself a human.
You say some cruel things, Araragi-kun,
despite knowing why I ended up like this.
And yet you tell me to just "suck it up"?
That's cruel. Heartless, even.
Aren't you going to show me any pity at all?
No.
You never found out who your biological father was, your mother committed suicide,
you got passed from family to family all over the place,
you failed to create any bonds with your step-parents and thus grew up in a cold household,
you still tried to force yourself to be a normal girl and—of all things—that's what you succeeded at.
Lady luck just isn't on your side at all, I swear.
You're really unfortunate, almost way too much so.
What's wrong with that, though?
You may be unfortunate, but that doesn't mean you have to suffer.
You may not be blessed, but that doesn't mean you have to sulk.
Even if bad things happen to you, just be strong!
You're going to go home after this acting like nothing had ever happened,
Hanekawa
and now that your parents are back, you're going to live the exact same life you've been leading up until now.
You're never, ever going to reconcile with them.
I guarantee it!
It's useless, even if you should miraculously chance upon happiness in the future.
You could end up on cloud nine for all I care, but that's not going to change the fact that you've had an unhappy past!
You'll remember that just as you're about to forget it.
You'll forever see it in your dreams!
The two of us are going to keep having nightmares for the rest of our lives!
Reality won't change a single bit!
It won't change...
I'm definitely not going to pity you.
Don't use some cat as a pretext.
Don't make an oddity your excuse.
Don't use misfortune as a springboard to growth.
At the end of the day, you're basically just hurting yourself.
Oddities don't actually exist, you know?
Weren't you going to
Scene no. 268
help me with my rehab?
They're fabrications!
What's gonna happen
Scene no. 268
if you go bad too?
If you still want to relieve some of that stress, I'll take care of that for you.
I'll fondle the heck out of your breasts whenever you want,
and I'll stare a hole through whichever part of your underwear-clad body you want me to.
Could you settle for that?
I'll make as much time for you as you need.
Because I'm your friend.
You really are the worst, Araragi-kun.
It makes my head hurt.
You're someone who can play a starring role but not a hero, right?
No, I can do neither.
The only role I can play is that of a vampire.
I even failed to become one though
Scene no. 276
So you won't do it.
Araragi
Scene no. 278
You won't play hero for me. You won't do it.
Araragi
Scene no. 278
I've been thinking about this for a while, but you actually hate me, don't you?
Yeah.
I hate your guts, Hanekawa.
I see.
And I actually hate yours too, Araragi-kun.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Die.
Go die.
Just go die.
I should just go die!
You'll take care of all my stress fur me?
How purrfectly delightful.
Can I kill you, then?
Sure, go ahead. It's what I want.
I want to die by your hand.
Really?
White
Unnumbered scene
Then die.
It hur—
It hurts!
White
Unnumbered scene
Araragi-kun!
What...
What did you do to me?!
You prepared... a sword?
That's right.
I swallowed it in advance,
like one of those old stage magicians.
But...
But Araragi-kun!
This pain is...
It doesn't hurt, right?
It doesn't hurt you.
That sword's called the Oddity Slayer.
It's a demonic sword, one I borrowed from a vampire, that slays only oddities.
It cut not you, but the Curse Cat inside you.
The Oddity Slayer only slays oddities
Scene no. 342
How can such a nonsensical sword even exist?
You didn't know about it, did you?
Even Oshino, a specialist, only found out a short while ago that she possessed such an insane sword.
It literally transcends human understanding.
A sword even Oshino-san didn't know about...
You definitely wouldn't have fallen for this if you knew such a killer item existed, right?
Having said that,
this really could've ended up as wishful thinking on my part.
Because there was a chance you could still have known about this sword's existence.
I'm relieved, Hanekawa.
Looks like you don't know everything either.
Then don't act like you do and give up on life!
Don't go spouting crap like how you should just go die!
You still have a ton of things you don't know about!
So say it like you always do:
"I don't know everything. I only know what I know."
I'm going to die.
I'm going to die by Hanekawa's hand.
I'm going to die for Hanekawa.
Oh man,
this makes me so happy.
I'm fully aware that this was an extremely foolish thing to do.
It serves no purpose.
The Oddity Slayer can exterminate the Curse Cat, sure,
but it's not going to help Hanekawa overcome her stress,
nor will it make the friction in her family disappear.
Oshino probably would've settled it in the very first round if he wanted things to end this way.
I'm pretty sure that's the second thing he wanted to warn me about earlier.
It's okay, though.
I didn't particularly want to save you anyway, Hanekawa.
Pointless and futile as it may be,
I want to die for you.
That's all there is to it.
White
Unnumbered scene
Did splitting Hanekawa from the Curse Cat using the demon sword cause an adverse reaction?
What the hell are you doing, Cat?
What's hurting Hanekawa going to achieve?
Didn't you go out of your way to help Hanekawa
because she didn't pity you at all when she found you run over and dead?
That's how it was for me too!
Araragi Koyomi
Scene no. 384
Back when I'd been attacked by a vampire and was no longer human,
Vampire
Scene no. 386
Human
Araragi Koyomi
Scene no. 386
Hanekawa didn't once pity or look down on me.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Scene no. 388
Classmate
Class president
Scene no. 388
She saw me as an equal!
Lifesaver
Scene no. 390
Isn't that right, Curse Cat?
White
Unnumbered scene
Even when lying dead on the street, or being hunted by vampires,
we're in no way pitiful, right?!
That's why you fell in love with Hanekawa too, right?!
So stop...
Stop hurting her like that!
Stop.
Please stop.
I beg of you, please stop!
What are you, stupid?
Yellow
Unnumbered scene
Everyone knows that forcibly pulling the plug tends to damage the hardware, servant of mine.
I started hearing
Scene no. 398
You sure did use my sword, my pride and joy, in an absurd manner.
What a preposterous way to chop up an oddity.
It almost makes me laugh.
hallucinations
Scene no. 401
Good heavens, servant of mine. You're only focusing on what's in front of you, like always.
You selfishly kept me alive, so don't you dare believe for one second that you can go off and die,
you oaf.
I'll show you how it's done, so just sit there and observe.
Obsesserve.
Obsesserve
Scene no. 413
Are you ready?
This is how you slay an oddity.
This is all right, isn't it?
It's all right this way, isn't it, Hanekawa?
We're a bunch of good-for-nothings.
Unbelievably unfortunate,
unreasonably unrewarded,
and completely incapable of righting the wrongs we make.
And that's how we'll stay for the rest of our lives,
but we're all right this way, aren't we?
No way. Absolutely not.
Scene no. 429
8th May
The next day,
I wolfed down my breakfast and left home on my bike.
I had to make a layover on my way to school.
Except bicycles
STOP
SLOW
Except light vehicles
Parking
Danger
Except public buses
28            60 min.
Railroad crossing
Now, then.
Black
Unnumbered scene
How am I supposed to pet her now?
Oh, that?
Vampire-chan demanded I buy it for her.
And, well, I gave it to her as a reward since she was the one who resolved that whole cat business in the end.
Quite the letdown.
It was a really short-lived dream.
By the way, Oshino.
Hanekawa...
She's fine, right?
Yeah, she's perfectly fine.
I can guarantee it.
Ms. Class Rep has no recollection at all of the things that happened this Golden Week.
Her memories as Black Hanekawa...
have been lost completely.
"Black Hanekawa?" What's that supposed to be?
New, modern
Hane
Black          kawa
That's what Ms. Class Rep had become.
The name is not more
Scene no. 450
You can't exactly refer to it as the Curse Cat.
The name is not less
Scene no. 450
Superbly
New variations need new names.
The name reflects what she is
Scene no. 450
The latest monster of the modern era,
Black Hanekawa.
Black Hanekawa
Scene no. 451
You suck so bad at naming things.
Very  very  very  black  Hanekawa Tsubasa
Scene no. 453
Apparently, Ms. Class Rep temporarily regained consciousness once she Energy Drained her parents.
Basically, her wish was granted at that point in time.
That's what it means, I guess.
Her wish...
She changed back almost immediately afterward, though.
Black
Unnumbered scene
No.
Ms. Class Rep wished for it so strongly that she dragged the cat,
which was already leaving her at that point,
back in and absorbed it even deeper.
That was the moment a new oddity—Black Hanekawa—was born.
Opportunistic idealist
Scene no. 463
She wanted the monster to take all the responsibility
Scene no. 465
I couldn't even die for Hanekawa
Scene no. 467
While we're on the subject of new types of monsters,
Hanekawa was always possessed by one, wasn't she?
A monster called family.
Family, eh?
But Ms. Class Rep doesn't consider her current parents to be family, does she?
That's exactly it.
Maybe the very concept of family is an oddity in Hanekawa's eyes.
Maybe.
Though, when I think about it, the fact that Hanekawa stayed the same even after she turned into a cat
really makes me wonder.
White
Unnumbered scene
Why don't you just marry her?
White
Unnumbered scene
What?
Like I said, why don't you just marry Ms. Class Rep?
That way, she'd get her hands on a real family at long last.
You know...
That's a terrible joke, Oshino.
Really?
I think it's a great idea.
It's a small price to pay for Ms. Class Rep extending a helping hand to you over spring break.
You seem to be forgetting that Hanekawa has feelings of her own.
Of course she does.
It's because she has feelings that she can be bewitched.
She can become a victim, and a culprit.
She can even become an oddity.
But you have your own feelings, don't you?
My own feelings...
I was convinced you were in love with Ms. Class Rep, you know.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Don't be stupid.
Black
Unnumbered scene
I'm not in love with Hanekawa.
Is that so?
Yeah.
Let's leave it at that.
Black
Unnumbered scene
That'd be for the best.
Black
Unnumbered scene
If you're fine with that, then sure.
I did ask how you felt, but Ms. Class Rep's feelings are much more important than yours.
No matter what the Curse Cat does,
no matter what you do,
when it comes down to it, she has to save herself.
Besides, Hanekawa's not even looking for help in the first place.
I wish she'd looked to me for help.
I would've done whatever it took, if she had only relied on me.
Maybe she did.
Huh?
It's not like people only look for help by saying "please help me."
In a similar vein, it's not like you're only in love with someone if you say "I love you."
Everyone has things they can't say on impulse.
Isn't that right, Araragi-kun?
I'm not at all worried.
I'm confident that I can respond to Hanekawa's usual smile with one of my own.
After all, it's not like I'm in love with her or anything.
I will never in my life say that I am.
Hanekawa.
Hanekawa-san...
Someday, I'll fall in love with someone other than you.
Naoetsu Private High School
I will, for the first time in my life, fall in love with someone other than you.
You showed me how to sympathize with others,
so there'll surely come a day when I fall in love with one of those people.
However, I will always look back on those nine days that you forgot,
those nine days that glittered like gold, with nostalgia.
I don't think I'll ever be able to forget them.
No matter what the future holds for me,
no matter what path I walk from now on,
these feelings I developed for you can never be denied.
They will forever stay the same.
That's how, during the Golden Week
of my third year of high school—
the May I spent as an eighteen year old—
I, Araragi Koyomi, saw something that wasn't my first love
come to a disappointing end.
And thus, I climb these stairs.
Cat Story
Cat
Tsubasa  Family
reached
the end
And in spite of that we
laugh knowingly as though we
planned it beforehand
Sigh if you want to
and take a deep breath then
Don't worry if it looks foolish
I will keep waiting
for what you wish for
Would it be a lie to say
that there is still time?
I don't want to be saved
I don't want to be rewarded
I just want to enjoy these fragile days
Every day I make my wishes
My experiences remain bittersweet
Far atop the horizon I felt
my fading daydream
Preview
Script: Nisio Isin
Illustrations: Haritama Hiroki
This is a preview hallucination.
Preview
Asking you
to watch the sequel too!
It's us!
The Fire Sisters!
Do you know what a shibanmushi is?
It's written with the characters for "death," "vigil," and "insect."
Preview
Impatient
Stir
Jeez
In English, it's called the Death Watch Beetle.
Man, it sounds way too cool in both Japanese and English!
Preview
Hi. My name is
Black Araragi.
I'll grant
all of
Araragi
Koyomi's
wishes.
Wriggle
It makes a ticking sound much like a clock,
Preview
Oh, good morning, Araragi!
Oh! That's the beloved Hanekawa.
Time to grant Koyomi's wish.
which commonly gets associated with a countdown to death.
That's why it's called the Death Watch Beetle.
Preview
Boob grab
Eek!
That clock sounds amazing!
Next Episode: Tsubasa Tiger Part One.
Preview
Next Episode
Tsubasa Tiger        Part One
I sentence that servant of mine not to keep vigil beside the dying, but to certain death.
Preview
Meow