Scene no. 1
Tsubasa
Inside the darkness
my love softly blossomed
like a flower for the first time
I'm sure you don't realize it
Tsubasa Family  Part Three
You held out your hand to me
and although I found no strength to take it
I want you to hold it out to me
for just a while longer
That is my ray of light in the darkness
I don't want to know the future
of my love just yet
Đây... không phải phòng của Hanekawa sao?
Ồ, Onī-chan, mừng anh về—
Có tất cả 6 phòng.
Thế nhưng...
trong ngôi nhà đó, trong nhà Hanekawa,
không có lấy một phòng cho
Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Hanekawa... vậy là xong rồi sao?
Liệu còn làm gì được nữa không?
Không cứu vãn được rồi.
Ngắn gọn là ngoài sức tưởng tượng!
Ngôi nhà đó,
gia đình đó,
mái nhà đó,
không xong rồi, hết hy vọng rồi!
Đùa~ Hết nói nổi luôn, cái ông Onī-chan này.
Ngoan ngoan, em biết anh sợ mà.
Đây, tới đi anh.
Vãi luôn!
Em gái vì đại nghĩa diệt thân như thế
mà anh làm cái gì vậy hả, Onī-chan!
Là tôi dạy cô đó!
Hai chị em cô sao lại bốc đồng thế hả!
Thế khác được à!
Là em gái của Onī-chan cơ mà!
Mà nói chung, bọn em lo đấy.
Chả thấy Onī-chan về gì cả.
Bọn em ở nhà còn lo là
anh gặp phải yêu ma hay gì đó luôn ấy.
Yêu ma?
Thì yêu ma mà, hay đúng hơn là yêu mèo.
Yêu mèo?
Dù mới chỉ là tin đồn nên chưa có gì chắc chắn,
nhưng họ kêu là có một con yêu mèo hình người
đang tấn công người dân khắp thành phố.
Energy Drain
Scene no. 110
Thế... họ đồn từ bao giờ?
Em nghe người ta đồn từ lúc trời chưa tối cơ.
Thế nên em mới lo cho Onī-chan,
rồi gọi lấy gọi để.
Tuy Onī-chan bình an vô sự
về nhà mừng rồi...
thế nhưng với cái tình trạng này,
với ý thức về chính nghĩa,
với tư cách thành viên của Fire Sisters
thì không thể làm ngơ được.
Karen-chan hiện đang
chuẩn bị đi săn yêu mèo đó.
Ấy...
Onī-chan, sao thế?
"Ấy" ý là gì?
Ấy... à thì...
anh là anh đang có chút vấn đề.
Chỉ riêng việc một mình đạp xe về nhà
giữa đêm hôm thế này đã đủ đáng sợ rồi,
mà giờ lại nghe kể về yêu mèo này nọ nữa
thì phải nói là sợ càng thêm sợ.
Anh thỏ đế lắm
không dám ngủ một mình đâu.
Nên đang tính hỏi xem Tsukihi-chan và Karen-chan
liệu có thể ngủ cùng anh vài hôm được không.
Nhưng nếu hai em
phải hành động vì chính nghĩa thì...
chắc anh đành chấp nhận thôi,
dù cho ngoài hai em ra
anh không còn biết dựa vào ai.
Gì cơ?
Không còn biết dựa vào ai sao?
Đã thế thì đành chịu thôi.
Trông anh sợ sệt thế này kể cũng tội,
nên thôi để em thuyết phục Karen-chan cho.
Vụ yêu mèo để cảnh sát lo đi.
Cảm ơn nha.
Scene no. 126
Chướng Miêu cứ bạ đâu rút đấy
với cái Bòn Rút Năng Lượng,
mình không tài nào hiểu được
mục đích của nó là gì.
Tuy nhiên, liệu mình có quyền được biết không?
Mà khoan, liệu mình có thực sự muốn biết không?
Mình đột nhập vào nhà Hanekawa,
khám phá ra câu chuyện trong đó,
và cũng chính mình đã phát điên lên.
Nói cho cùng, trên thế giới này
có những điều không cần phải biết.
Nếu đã ích kỷ ngưỡng mộ người ta,
rồi lại ích kỷ cảm thấy vỡ mộng,
thì thà từ đầu,
không nên biết luôn chăng?
Lúc đó, có lẽ mình...
không nên dính dáng quá nhiều
đến Hanekawa chăng?
Có lẽ không nên để ý đến miếng gạc.
Tuy nhiên...
Đó chỉ như...
"muối đổ lòng ai, người nấy xót" mà thôi.
Mình chỉ muốn thích cậu ấy,
kỳ vọng vào cậu ấy, ngưỡng mộ cậu ấy...
Hồi nghỉ xuân,
cậu ấy đã làm đủ thứ để cứu mình.
Dù đã vắt óc suy nghĩ
nhưng vẫn không tài nào hiểu nổi.
Cơ mà có một điều chắc chắn.
Đó là mình không biết gì về cậu ấy cả.
Vậy mà gọi là yêu ư?
Nực cười!
Và giờ thì lại càng xấu hổ hơn
khi nhớ về lần tâm sự với Tsukihi lúc trước.
Dù vậy, ngay lúc này đây,
khi nghĩ về Hanekawa,
ngực mình như vỡ tung.
1st  May
Ngày 1 tháng 5... và cả...
Ngày 2 tháng 5, Hanekawa đều không đi học.
2nd May             (Sat)
Đến ngày mùng 2 khi tan học,
tin đồn về yêu mèo đã rộ lên khắp trường,
Naoetsu Private High School
trong đó không ít người
đã tận mắt chứng kiến.
Tức là Chướng Miêu
đã hoạt động rất năng suất.
Ngày mai, ngày 5 tháng 3
là bước vào kỳ nghỉ, nhưng trước đó,
tôi quyết đinh đến chỗ tòa nhà bỏ hoang
nơi Oshino ở một lần nữa.
O-Oshino!
Ây dà, Araragi-kun.
Ta đợi cậu mãi.
Ta cứ đinh ninh là cậu sẽ tới sớm hơn cơ.
Và ta cũng muốn bình phục trở lại
trước khi cậu đến.
Nhưng đống băng gạc kỳ diệu
thì hôm nọ dùng hết cho Araragi-kun rồi còn đâu.
Oshino? Rốt cuộc đã có chuyện gì?
Có chuyện gì ấy à?
Có gì đâu, chả có chuyện gì cả.
Chỉ là ta thua thôi.
T-Thua? Thua gì cơ?
Hiển nhiên rồi còn.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Là thua Chướng Miêu đó.
Trong khoảng 3 ngày tính từ hôm 30 tháng 4,
ta và nó chiến đâu đó tầm 20 trận.
Và ta thua tầm 20 lần.
Thế là thua hết rồi còn gì.
Thì thua hết mà,
giờ chỉ còn là cái bóng của chính mình.
Chịu đấy!
Nữ sinh cấp ba mặc nội y mà cứ khơi khơi ra như thế
thì trung niên như ta hại thận lắm.
Trên bảo dưới không nghe
thì đánh đấm cái nỗi gì.
Chịu!
Đến cái tuổi mà từ trong ra ngoài
đều đã lụi tàn héo úa thế này,
thì đừng có mà bòn rút nữa chứ.
T-Thế nó mạnh tới vậy à?
Chướng Miêu ấy.
Đến cả ông, dân chuyên rồi mà còn bị...
À không, mạnh cái nỗi gì.
Hôm nọ ta có nói qua rồi đấy,
không có chuyện nó chung mâm với
con Ma cà rồng đã tấn công Araragi-kun,
hay đúng hơn, việc đem nó ra so sánh
là đủ xúc phạm rồi, nó quá tép riu.
Khoan, khoan.
Đúng là ông có đề cập đến chuyện
nó không có cửa với Ma cà rồng,
nhưng có thấy ông đả động gì đến
hai chữ tép riu đâu.
Ta không nói là bởi nếu
Araragi-kun mà biết kiểu gì chả xin được hỗ trợ.
Nên đơn giản là không tiết lộ thôi.
Ngay cả dân gà mờ cũng có thể giải quyết được
nếu chịu động não.
Chướng Miêu yếu tới vậy đó.
Nhưng...
Dĩ nhiên!
Không vì thế mà ta nương tay hay khinh địch.
Ta đã đánh hết sức.
Nhưng vẫn thua.
Chướng Miêu là tép riu.
Giả vờ chết trên đường,
ám những người đến cứu vì lòng thương cảm.
Là yêu ma thế chỗ của nạn nhân.
Dạng Quái Dị chiếm hữu cơ thể.
Giống như Thần Nghèo,
chúng kéo chủ nhân vào vực sâu thống khổ.
Để mà nói thì,
nó cũng như bao yêu ma khác thôi.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Tuy nhiên, người bị ám lại là bé lớp trưởng,
nên vụ này nó mới bất thường như thế.
Chướng Miêu vốn chỉ là hạng tép riu,
mà giờ đã trở nên vô vùng mạnh.
Không cẩn thận, nó thậm chí có thể
sáng ngang được với Mà cà rồng.
Chia sẻ cơ thể thì đã đành,
đây lại còn cả những thứ trong đầu nữa thì hỏng rồi.
Các cách truyền thống
mà ta dùng để đối phó với Quái Dị,
từ thủ thuật, đến phương pháp,
tất cả đều vứt vào sọt rác.
Cô bé có kiến thức của một chuyên gia.
Cô bé cái gì cũng biết.
Quái Dị mà tấn công con người
với đầy đủ chiến lược các thứ,
Lần đầu ta thấy.
Dù đã lường trước được vấn đề,
nhưng quả nhiên là bé lớp trưởng
không hề bình thường tí nào.
Tấn công con người một cách thuần thục như vậy,
Quái Dị đào đâu ra.
Từ từ đã.
"Tấn công con người một cách thuần thục"?
Oshino, ông nói cứ như kiểu
đây là chủ đích của Hanekawa vậy.
À thì, ta đoán thế.
Chướng Miêu vốn có phải loại Quái Dị như vậy đâu.
Có điều, Araragi-kun.
Việc ta gặp khó khăn đến vậy,
thực ra cũng không hẳn là diễn biến quá tồi tệ.
Với diễn biến này, có thể nói rằng
bé lớp trưởng vẫn còn ở đâu đó bên trong Chướng Miêu.
Ta cho là vậy.
Ít nhất,
nếu bé lớp trưởng mà bị
Chướng Miêu chiếm lấy cả thể xác lẫn tâm trí,
thì đã không có cái diễn biến này.
Có lẽ ý thức của bé lớp trưởng vẫn đọng lại
tương đối nhiều bên trong Chướng Miêu.
Thế nên nó mới mạnh vậy.
Đây là tin xấu nhất từ trước đến giờ,
nhưng cũng đồng thời đem lại hy vọng.
Tại sao? Hy vọng ở đâu?
À thì bởi...
nếu bị chiếm hoàn toàn, thì chấm hết rồi còn đâu.
Chỉ còn nước phải giết.
Trong khi bé lớp trưởng vẫn còn ý thức,
phải giải cứu bằng được ý thức đó,
phải giải thoát cô bé khỏi yêu mèo,
nếu không Hanekawa Tsubasa,
người bạn trân quý nhất của Araragi-kun,
sẽ bốc hơi khỏi thế giới này.
Scene no. 212
Once upon a time, there was a white cat lying dead on the road.
Finding that cat pitiable, a passerby buried it and prayed for it.
From that night onward, that virtuous man's behavior took a turn for the worse.
Admitting that he was now out of control,
the people around him summoned an exorcist in a bid to exorcise the cat that had possessed him.
Now here's the punch line.
This is where the Curse Cat bares its fangs.
It turns out that the virtuous man hadn't been possessed by a cat at all.
Black
Unnumbered scene
A twist, or an absurd conclusion...
Call it what you want, but this is an
oddity tale that comes with a lesson of sorts.
A human being made exclusively of virtue cannot possibly exist.
Kindness is nothing but the tip of the iceberg that is a person.
There is always a counterpart.
If there be light, then there is darkness; if white, black.
It's an anecdote that sees right through human nature.
Why a cat, though?
Because a cat's always going to come out of the bag, of course.
And the cat's certainly out of the bag for Ms. Class Rep.
A human who is perfectly fair and virtuous does not exist.
Instead, it's because she insists on being one that her stress becomes piled up,
unleashing her dark side.
Normally the cat would only serve as a mask of sorts, but for whatever reason,
Ms. Class Rep has pretty much become united with the Curse Cat.
If we consider the cat to be the dominant party,
then maybe it would be better to call it assimilation.
A formidable opponent indeed.
Or should I say, invincible?
It'll spell big trouble if we don't end this soon.
We're in real danger of reaching an outcome where it turns out she hadn't been possessed by a cat at all.
We have to do something before she completely merges with the cat.
3rd May - Constitution Day
Naoetsu Private High School
Red
Unnumbered scene
The well-endowed Hanekawa-san always pushes her breasts against this desk, doesn't she?
What are you, a purrvert without limits?
How frightening. You're scarier than an oddity.
You just furvently licked a girl's desk and got all aroused.
No, that's not it!
More importantly, where did you come from? How did you get into this classroom?
More impurrtantly?
What on earth could be more impurrtant than you licking my master's desk, human?
I have no idea what you're talking about!
Say whatever you want, I'm not going to admit anything in court!
Meowhaha
Hmm? What?
I don't sense much hostility from your expression, human.
Well, that's because there isn't much I could do to you anyway, Cat.
Besides, it's not like you're going to kill me,
right?
Who kneows?
My Energy Drain is part and parcel of who I am,
and not a skill I can freely use, let alone control.
I could go easy on someone, but the extent of which is out of my hands.
It's possible that I might kill someone without even intending to.
Still, I much prefer this to having you bite or claw away at me the moment we run into each other.
I'd be done for in an instant if you did that again.
A vampire, huh?
Meowhaha
Vampire
A top-class oddity that I originally wouldn't even dream of locking claws with.
But thanks to my master's knowledge of strategy and tactics,
I've become an existence capable of overwhelming even an oddity specialist.
I appreciate it, fur real.
I'm not one to return a favor.
I'm more the type of oddity that'd bite the hand that feeds it.
Fur this case, however, I'm so grateful to her I might make an exception.
Vampire
Black
Unnumbered scene
Well, vampires and you might both possess Energy Drain as a special trait,
but I'm sure they don't work the same way.
A vampire's Energy Drain is a meal,
Meal
Scene no. 275
whereas the Curse Cat's is a curse.
Curse
Scene no. 275
Purrcisely.
What I don't get, though, is why you're indiscriminately attacking people.
If we're going to talk about different types of oddities here, the Curse Cat isn't one that would do that, right?
Hey, Cat. You...
Oh, it's not impurrtant.
Just fur a distraction, that's all.
Huh?
I'm only attacking people fur a distraction.
This is basically the same thing as ringing the doorbell and running away,
or clawing graffiti on the walls.
A stress buster!
A stress buster?
Wait, huh?
What does that mean?
"What does it mean?"
It means exactly what it says on the can.
You did notice the appurrance of that house on the inside, right?
That house?
Where my master lives.
I know you did.
Cats have a pretty good sense of smell, you know.
I go back fur a change of clothes, and what
do I find? Your scent, all over the place.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Fur fifteen years, my master has lived in that home—that household.
You can just imagine how much purressure that was putting her under, can't you?
Playing purranks on the good people of this town provides her some relief.
That's all there is to it.
These purranks have nothing to do with curses.
How so?
Are oddities even capable of such behavior?
Being a possessive type of oddity, I've usurped my master's body.
Which means I've usurped her mind as well,
so I know what kind of life my master has led fur the past fifteen years in that house.
That's why I'm lending her a helping paw with her stress busting.
But if those are your reasons, you don't need to attack people unrelated to this, do you?
Unfurtunately, this is the only way I know how to do things.
Evil deeds are fun.
They're fun because they cause trouble fur complete strangers.
There's no logic to it, but it's not illogical either.
At the very least, as the inverse and darker side of her,
I'm a lot more mellow meow, don't you think?
Compared to when I tore your arm off, I mean.
I did notice that, yeah.
See? It means what I'm doing is having a positive effect.
That's how it is, so rest assured.
This stress busting will end if I attack another five hundred people or so.
And at that time, I, as an oddity, will disappurr,
having carried out my duties and repaid my debt.
So tell that old man with the Hawaiian shirt not to interfere.
I don't really get it, but he wants to help my master out, doesn't he?
So tell him to leave her to me.
Why would you go that far?
Aren't you just an evil spirit that's possessed Hanekawa?
You shouldn't have any reason to go out of your way to help her.
I've been telling you fur a while that this is all so I can repay my debt to her, even if it's out of character.
It was all a tall tail, though.
To be purrfectly honest, apart from her sharing her knowledge with me,
I don't really have a reason to feel indebted to my master.
What're you talking about?
Didn't Hanekawa bury you when you were lying dead after getting run over?
Isn't that how you imposed yourself on her? By taking advantage of her kindness and compassion?
Meow that's not true.
On the surface, the event itself happened fur sure.
My master picked me up when I was lying dead on the road,
moved me to a location with a nice view, and buried me there.
You aren't mistaken in your knowledge of the event itself.
The cat's grave
Scene no. 333
However, my master held no sympurrthy for me at all at the time.
She held a funeral fur me thinking it was the most obvious thing in the world to do.
Completely unsentimental.
It was like she had no pity fur me at all.
So in truth, nothing was there fur me to take advantage of.
But wait, Hanekawa was—
My master's only desire is to be a normal girl.
"If you find a dead cat by the road, bury it."
Well, that's the purrfectly right thing to do.
You could even call it a law, or a furmula.
So she obeyed that law. Followed that furmula.
That's all there was to it.
Normally, there's no way one can abide by those rules.
Most people wouldn't think about burying a dead cat,
even if they knew it was the right, lovely thing to do.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Scene no. 344
No, they might think about it,
but they wouldn't actually do it.
They would have neither the heart nor the ability to.
However, Hanekawa will pull it off.
Hanekawa can
Scene no. 345
never ever become
a normal girl
Scene no. 345
That's right. She'll pull it off.
Her emotions won't come into play at all.
She won't feel a thing.
She can carry out her morals like a machine.
I've been given several funerals, but none on purr with hers.
Almost too black
Scene no. 345
That's why I felt inclined to save her.
A Stygian blackness
Scene no. 346
Classroom
In short, it's just a whim of mine.
Cat-like, right?
So make sure to pass on my message.
Tell that Hawaiian bastard to overlook my pranks if he doesn't want to be sued for animal cruelty.
It's the least he could do fur me, considering I've let him do as he pleased all this time.
What's that supposed to mean?
You already know, don't you?
Scene no. 352
I would've killed him in the very first round if I,
If I
Scene no. 353
or rather my master
or rather my master,
had any
Scene no. 354
real intention
to harm him
Scene no. 354
had any real intention to harm him.
I've been holding back in all of our catfights because he's an acquaintance of hers.
As for you...
Well, it doesn't look like you're planning on doing anything.
Yeah, that's the right answer.
The right thing to do fur you, if you want to help my master out, is to do nothing.
You don't purrticularly want to die, do you?
See ya, human.
You... should try your best to lead a happy nine lives.
Wait!
Hmm?
If relieving Hanekawa of her stress is your objective,
I'll tell you right now that it's impossible.
Huh? Why?
Hanekawa's parents are the ones causing her all that stress, right?
Even if you released all of it for her, it'd only start accumulating again once she went back home.
You could attack five hundred strangers, or keep stress busting
for a month, but sooner or later you'd be back to square one.
Hmm?
Yeah, that's right.
In that case, I'll just have to keep beating them up fur her until they stop coming back.
I won't let it end with just the Energy Drain meow.
I'll simply respond to domewstic violence with some of my own,
if that's what my master wants.
As if—
Yup. That's the right choice.
You'll be cursed the moment you caress me.
That's why I'm the Curse Cat.
Stay away from me.
Don't put even a single finger on me.
The right choice here is to not get involved with me
and, probably,
not with my master either.
Cat, you...
I'll catch you later.
Lead a happy life.
This is hopeless.
I really do...
like Hanekawa.
I like her so much I can't bring myself to touch her.
I like her.
I wondered if I liked her, felt I did, and realized I did.
But yeah, Tsukihi-chan was right.
I really do like her, unbearably so,
but these feelings of mine aren't what you'd call love.
Red
Unnumbered scene
They'd gone way past love.
Black
Unnumbered scene
Love
Curse cat
Hanekawa
Love
Curse cat
Hanekawa
Meowhaha
Vampire
Hanekawa
Meowhaha
Vampire
Hanekawa
Black
Unnumbered scene
Forget wanting to always be with her...
Right now I want to die for Hanekawa.
And in spite of that we
laugh knowingly as though we
planned it beforehand
Sigh if you want to
and take a deep breath then
Don't worry if it looks foolish
I will keep waiting
for what you wish for
Would it be a lie to say
that there is still time?
I don't want to be saved
I don't want to be rewarded
I just want to enjoy these fragile days
Every day I make my wishes
My experiences remain bittersweet
Far atop the horizon I felt
my fading daydream
Preview
Script: Nisio Isin
Illustrations: Haritama Hiroki
This is a preview hallucination.
Preview
Thanks for
making the
first volume a huge hit.
It's us!
The Fire Sisters!
They might not be immortal, sure,
but Planarians keep regenerating no matter how many times you cut them. Quite astounding, don't you think?
Preview
Meow
We finally
settled that issue.
Then again, things'd end up getting rather messy if vampires regenerated like that.
Preview
Huh? What's wrong, Bro?
Wait a second!
Just think about it. If their arm got ripped off, they'd just grow another one.
Preview
Tap Tap
What?! You want to take some pictures?!
And the ripped-off arm would grow another body.
They'd multiply!
The world would be filled with vampires like me or that servant of mine.
Preview
Shiny
All I want is to relieve
some of my sexual frustration.
It's just that this
high school girl with cat ears,
wearing only her underwear,
is driving me crazy with lust.
Disgusting!
Next Episode: Tsubasa Family Part Four
Preview
Next Episode
Tsubasa  Family      Part  Four
I wonder how many more would spring up in just this episode.
Preview
Huh?
Where am I?
Now he can't do anything bad.