Scene no. 1
Let's recall the events of that ominous Golden Week that I spent flirting with Hanekawa Tsubasa to my heart's content.
They are bitter memories, they are sour memories, but somewhere deep down there's sweetness to be found.
Let's recall the events of those nine golden days, events that I want to forget if possible,
and even if not, I want to undo them.
Timewise, it was during the two weeks of my spring break between my second and third years in high school,
during the month I experienced hell itself; it was such a time.
She was bewitched by a cat.
A cat.
A felid, a carnivore, a mammal.
Ever since, I can't stand cats.
I'm afraid of cats.
Yes, just as I'm afraid of Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Now please let me tell you about a dream I saw last night.
Scene no. 1
29th April, Saturday, morning
What the hell did you go back to sleep for?
Die.
Araragi
Ts-Tsukihi! What on earth are you doing?!
You trying to kill me?!
A brother who'd fall asleep after that is better off dead.
It's unfathomable that you could go back to sleep after Karen-chan and I went out of our way to wake you up.
You should just drop dead.
You should just drop dead!
What's with this drastic change in personality?!
My character's kind of bland compared to the others,
so I wanted to try out being a yandere.
That was more of a psychopath than a yandere!
Golden Week starts today, huh?
There's nothing at all to look forward to.
You're being quite pessimistic on the very first day, aren't you?
Not even nine hours have passed since Golden Week began, y'know.
Oh, right.
Let's have a discussion about love, Tsukihi-chan.
Love?
Inside the darkness
my love softly blossomed
like a flower for the first time
I'm sure you don't realize it
Tsubasa Family     Part One
You held out your hand to me
and although I found no strength to take it
I want you to hold it out to me
for just a while longer
That is my ray of light in the darkness
I don't want to know the future
of my love just yet
Episode Forbidden
Tsubasa  Family
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Kneel
Scene no. 34
So, what kind of love discussion are we having here?
You're in middle school and have a boyfriend already,
and you're probably a veteran of giving relationship advice to your friends,
so you're the only one I can ask about this.
There's a girl in my class who I'm interested in.
I might have feelings for a girl who ended up in the same class as me.
Oh, wow!
Is it that surprising?
Of course it is!
Surprising? It's a bombshell, if you ask me!
My brother, who used to make ridiculous declarations like,
Colored artwork
"The more friends you make, the weaker you become as a person" is in love with someone now?!
This is as shocking to me as a talking dog!
Don't get ahead of yourself.
I only said that I might, perhaps, be interested in her. It's not set in stone.
That's why I'm here, reluctantly asking you for advice.
Let's say there's a member of the opposite sex.
How do you figure out if you're in love with them?
Scene no. 51
Er, what?
Could you repeat that?
You didn't catch that?
Pay attention this time.
How does one figure out if they're in love with a member of the opposite sex?
Basically, at what point do the normal feelings you have for someone turn into affection?
Hate                                                            Neutral                                                            Love
Playing the straight man is usually your role and not mine, but in this case...
You're saying you don't know if you're in love?
What are you, a girl?!
Sit up straight!
Sit up straight
Scene no. 64
I want a proper explanation for all this, stupid brother of mine.
Er... I can't really go into specifics, but—
Scene no. 65
Let's call the subject H-san, for the time being.
H-san? Awfully specific, aren't we?
Ever since we ended up in the same class at the beginning of the month,
HỒI          TƯỞNG
she's all I've been thinking about.
H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san
And it's not just thinking, either.
During class, whenever I take my eyes off the blackboard,
I always find myself looking in her direction.
And it's not just in school, either.
I look for her on my way to school and back, too.
Even when I go shopping to, let's say, the bookstore,
Yaharu Bookstore
Law
Qualifications, Jobs
there's a part of me that hopes we'll run into each other since this is such a small town.
Nutritious recipes
How to cook for someone ill
Recipes
and western-style sweets
Japanese Literature
Floor guide for the 1st floor
Kobe
Chugoku
Shikoku
Kyushu
Okinawa
Reading a book I bought at that bookstore makes me think,
"Oh, I bet she'd like this part," and so on.
Then His-Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness said to the old man: "If this be thy daughter, wilt thou offer her to me?" He replied, saying: "With reverence, but I know not thy august name." Then be replied, saying: "I am elder brother to the Heaven-Shining-Great-August deity. So I hath now descended from Heaven." Then the deities Foot-Stroking-Elder and Hand-Stroking-Elder said: "If that be so, with reverence will we offer her to thee." So His-Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness, at once taking and changing, the young girl into a multitudinous and close-toothed comb which he stuck into his august hair-bunch, said to the deities Foot-Stroking-Elder and Hand-Stroking-Elder: "Do you distill some eightfold refined liquor? Also make a fence round about, in that fence make eight gates, at each gate tie together eight platforms, on each platform put a liquor-vat, and into each vat pour the eightfold refined liquor, and wait." So as they waited after having thus prepared everything in accordance with his bidding the eight-forked serpent came truly as the old man had said, and immediately dipped a head into each vat, and drank the liquor. Thereupon it was intoxicated with drinking, and all the heads lay down and slept. Then His-Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness drew the ten-grasp saber that was augustly girded on him, and cut the serpent in pieces, so that the River Hi flowed on changed into a river of blood. So when he cut the middle tail, the edge of his august sword broke. Then, thinking it strange, he thrust into and split the flesh with the point of his august sword and looked, and there was a great sword within. So he took this great sword, and, thinking it a strange thing, he respectfully informed the Heaven-Shining-Great-August deity. This was the Herb-Quelling Great Sword. So thereupon His Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness sought in the land of Idzumo for a place where he might build a palace. Then he arrived at a place called Suga, and said: "On coming to this place my august heart is pure," and in that place he built a palace to dwell in. So that place is now called Suga. When this great deity, first built the palace of Suga, clouds rose up thence. Then he made an august song. That song said: "Eight clouds arise. The eightfold fence of Idzumo makes an eightfold fence for the spouses to retire within. Oh, that eightfold fence." Then he called the Deity Foot-Stroking-Elder and said: "Thee do I appoint Headman of my palace," and moreover bestowed on him the name of Master-of-the-Temple-of-Inada-Eight-Eared-Deity-of-Suga. And again, having wedded the Divine-Princess-of-Great-Majesty, daughter of the Deity Great-Mountain-Possessor, he begot children: the Great-Harvest Deity and the August-Spirit-of-Food. The elder brother, the Deity Eight-Island-Ruler wedded Princess-Falling-Like-the-Flowers-of-the-Trees, daughter of the Deity Great-Mountain-Possessor, and
I'd think about buying a porn magazine,
but then immediately put it back on the shelf,
because I'd be afraid she'd come to hate me if I bought it.
You don't have to be so frank about it.
That's way too much personal information.
More like, do you really think I want to hear about you hesitating to buy porn?
Actually, Onii-chan...
What?
That's love, isn't it?
You never know.
I've never even fallen in love with someone in the first place.
Never?!
Not once.
Kneel
Scene no. 89
I figured I'd use your case as a reference.
Your boyfriend... Rousokuzawa-kun, was it?
I'm surprised you remember.
Just his name, though.
When, and at what stage, did you conclude you were in love with him?
That's what I really wanted to ask you about.
Well, I did,
somehow.
Somehow?
Yup. Ambiguously. Vaguely.
Is that really okay?
It is. That's how it works.
Okay, then let's leave the timing part aside for now and focus on the reason.
Rousokuzawa
Scene no. 104
Why did you fall in love with Rousokuzawa-kun?
One reason or another.
I really just did.
Somehow
Somehow, for one reason or another, I just did.
I wondered if I loved him, felt I did, and realized I did.
Something like that.
How vague could you possibly get?
The same goes for the reasons as well.
You could make up loads of excuses like how he's so cool, nice, tall, rich, or whatever.
You can come up with reasons like that,
but they're all just lies.
Lies you say to try to justify your feelings.
Pretense, in other words. In the end, they're just excuses.
You begin by concluding that you're in love,
then climb a ladder to reach that conclusion.
A ladder?
Maybe a rocket would be more fitting given the situation.
Yeah, it's like building a rocket.
I think you're pretty much in love if you always want to be with someone.
I see.
Then maybe I, Araragi Koyomi-kun, have finally fallen in love at the ripe old age of eighteen.
Why stop at "maybe"? Go all the way!
Go  all  the  way!
Scene no. 124
Yaybe!
Scene no. 125
Yaybe...
Yaybe......
Scene no. 126
You fell in love! It's decided!
You mean it?!
Yes. No uncertainty about it!
I hereby declare that you're in love with H-san.
Well, if that's your decision, there's not much I can do about it. Yep.
All right! I no longer have any doubts!
You have my gratitude. Thank you, Tsukihi-chan.
Gratitude
Scene no. 133
No, no, no. It was a big deal, but then it wasn't, really.
Well, I said quite a lot, but if you take anything away from this...
Know that falling in love with someone is as ordinary as a dog barking,
so it's not worth worrying about so much.
I see. Ordinary, eh?
Yup. Completely normal.
It's normal to be interested in a girl in your class.
Scene no. 138
Normal!
Normal
Scene no. 139
Paying more attention to her than the blackboard during a class is normal too.
Scene no. 140
Normal!
Normal
Scene no. 141
As is looking for her on the way to school and back,
Scene no. 142
wondering if you'll run into her,
and letting your imagination run wild when purchasing a book!
Normal!
Scene no. 143
Normal
The same goes for wanting to fondle her breasts, too!
Scene no. 144
Nope.
Scene no. 145
Nope
What on earth are you talking about, Tsukihi-chan?
What am I talking about?
Maybe you should sit up straight, too.
Okay. Got it.
Sit up straight
Scene no. 152
What I'm saying is,
Sit up straight
Scene no. 152
H-san has breasts appealing enough to make one want to cop a feel,
or fondle them.
What I'm saying is, H-san has breasts appealing enough to
That's where we're at right now.
I'm sorry, but could you please stop using such lewd terminology?
Hmm?
Okay, then how about touch gently?
Well okay, that's not lewd and even sounds kind of cute, but—
Scene no. 158
Anyway, the long and short of it is
that I keep wanting to gently touch H-san's breasts.
This is what you call love, right?
Nope.
Nope
Scene no. 162
But think about it this way.
You wouldn't want to touch the breasts of a girl you don't love, would you?
So these feelings of mine must be what you'd call love.
A boy wanting to touch a girl's breasts is natural, so you shouldn't overthink it.
Sheesh.
Sheesh, sheesh.
What?
I figured we'd try it out.
Here, cop a feel.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Scene no. 169
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Scene no. 169
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Scene no. 169
Okay.
Not  a  touch  but  a  catch
Scene no. 176
It hurts, dammit!
Red
Unnumbered scene
I said it hurts! Let go! Let go this very instant!
Ah, geez.
You went too far fondling your sister's breasts there!
Breast
warning
Ah, geez. You went too far fondling your sister's breasts there!
What were you even expecting?
Where did you think this was gonna go
Ah, geez. You went too far fondling your sister's breasts there!
when you stuck your breasts out at me?
It was both a joke and a test of sorts.
In my head,
I foresaw us engaging back and forth,
with you trying to prove your theory right
by saying you had no interest in breasts like these,
and me pointing out that it's only because they're your sister's.
Would've made for a great scene, but you blew it.
So what now?
What do you mean?
What conclusion do we derive from that test or whatever it was?
Er...
Aren't you just sexually frustrated?
What?!
Come to think of it,
didn't you say that you couldn't buy porn mags, you couldn't
buy porn mags, and that you couldn't buy porn mags earlier?
I didn't say it thrice.
That backfired on you.
Backfired completely.
You mistook your libido for feelings of love,
and now you're caught in an inflationary spiral of sexual frustration.
Holy crap. An inflationary spiral?
You're saying that a James Bond-like phenomenon is now occurring inside my head?
Yup. That's why you end up indiscriminately touching even your sister's chest.
I did end up touching it, huh?
That touchscreen-like chest of yours, I mean.
Aren't touchscreens flat surfaces?!
I see. I'm sexually frustrated, huh?
But yeah, that's quite a convincing argument, now that I think about it.
Actually, I get the feeling that's exactly what's going on here.
Tsukihi: "It was good, wasn't it?"
Koyomi: "It wasn't bad."
Scene no. 212
Tsukihi: "It was good, wasn't it?"
Koyomi: "It wasn't bad."
Scene no. 212
Tsukihi: "It was good, wasn't it?"
Koyomi: "It wasn't bad."
Scene no. 212
Tsukihi: "It was good, wasn't it?"
Koyomi: "It wasn't bad."
Scene no. 212
Tsukihi: "It was good, wasn't it?"
Koyomi: "It wasn't bad."
Scene no. 212
I get it now. So that's what was happening to me.
Yeah. That was a close one, wasn't it?
You nearly mistook finding someone's breasts appealing for falling in love with someone you don't even like.
Oh man.
This is what all of them mean when they say, "D-Don't get the wrong idea, okay?" Right?
Looking at it from H-san's point of view in this case, that'd be a very serious request.
Either way, now that we've reached a conclusion,
we'd better come up with some countermeasures.
That's right.
Scene no. 223
This could end up becoming a disaster if we neglect it.
I guess I was lucky I realized the truth after a single touch
Scene no. 223
We must protect H-san from my demonic hands.
That's right.
Scene no. 224
I suppose I could settle for clearing my head by fondling you or Karen-chan whenever I feel like it.
That's not something that can be put into practice!
What, aren't you Fire Sisters the warriors of justice?
You should gladly sacrifice yourselves for me, then.
I get the feeling that sacrificing you is the only way to administer justice in this case.
There's no way I'm letting you fondle my breasts for such a flimsy and selfish reason.
What do we do, then?
Well, I suppose you don't have a choice...
Go buy a porn magazine.
That's the conclusion?
Scene no. 234
I mean, you hesitated to buy them this past month because you've been worried H-san would judge you for it.
And considering it's you we're talking about here,
you probably threw away the prized collection you built up over time just to cleanse your body and mind, right?
H-How'd you know?!
That's just increasing your pent-up frustration.
So you should solve that problem by purchasing a new porn magazine.
Now that we've come to an agreement, go strike while the iron's hot!
The bookstore should be opening right about now too, so go buy some.
I'm home!
Welcome back.
What, is it raining?
And I was just about to go out, too.
No, it's not raining.
It's weather appropriate for the first day of Golden Week: clear blue skies.
Why are you so drenched, then?
Oh, this is just sweat.
That's all sweat?
Are you serious?
Well, you see, I don't go jogging too often, so I'm not accustomed to pacing myself.
Apparently, I got it completely wrong this time.
I didn't expect it to be that far...
42.195 kilometers, that is.
Did you just run a full marathon?!
I went jogging today to commemorate the start of Golden Week, so I imagined myself as an Olympic torchbearer.
Olympic torchbearers don't run 42.195 kilometers!
Man, I'm beat.
Thirsty as hell too. I need some water!
Guess I'll take a shower now.
Hey, Karen-chan.
What is it?
I want you to enlighten me on something.
Do you finally feel inclined to take up the way of karate?
No, I don't want you to teach me your secret technique.
How do you figure out if you're in love... if you love someone?
Huh? It's love advice you're looking for?
If looking at their face makes you want to have their babies,
you're in love with them. It's that simple.
Scene no. 278
Taxi
Yo, Araragi-kun!
You doin' all right?
Yo! I'm doin' all right, yes.
Failure
Scene no. 297
Er,
Scene no. 300
you see, Araragi-kun—
Red
Unnumbered scene
What's a high schooler like you thinking, flipping skirts at this age?
You see, Hanekawa...
Don't worry, I know.
Here.
You're kind, Araragi-kun.
You're kind, and you're a nice guy.
That's what I like about you.
Let's take a walk.
You have younger sisters, don't you?
Yeah.
Two sisters the world would never miss.
Never miss?
Having said that, they're my family, so it's not like we're on bad terms.
But they really are causing me tons of trouble.
Although, I guess there have been times when I've been the instigator.
So you're in the same boat?
I'd say that's what family's all about.
Family?
Right. Family.
Did I ever tell you I was an only child?
No, I don't think you did.
You see, Araragi-kun...
I don't have what you'd call a family.
Easy there, Hanekawa.
You can't say you don't have a family just because you don't have siblings.
Surely you have a dad, a mom, grandparents—
I don't.
I don't have a dad, a mom, or anyone else for that matter.
Basically, my biological mother's husband's second wife is my current mother,
and her second husband's my current father.
So they're not your biological parents?
Right. The dad and mom I'm living with right now aren't related to me by blood at all. They're complete strangers.
No kindred of mine, if you will.
"They're not related to me by blood, so they're no kindred of mine"?
Sounds like the kind of thing that'd make a vampire laugh, doesn't it?
Not at all.
I used to think it was possible to become a family even if you weren't blood-related.
I used to think I had to try my best to get along well with them.
But things just didn't go my way.
Nothing ever goes my way. It's annoying.
That bruise on your face...
Who did that to you?
Why? Why would you, Araragi-kun, ask me that question?
That's...
That's probably because I'm your friend.
Friend...
Wouldn't a friend usually ask questions in these kinds of situations?
I'm not really sure, though.
Hmm, yeah. You're probably right.
Do you promise not to tell anyone?
Well, oka—
When I say anyone, I mean anyone.
Not your sisters, nor anyone else in your family.
Will you keep it a secret from everyone?
I... promise.
My dad hit me this morning.
He hit you? That's—
Just put yourself in his shoes for a second, Araragi-kun.
You're around forty years of age,
and you have to put up with a seventeen year old you don't even know talking to you like she knows everything.
Don't you think it's inevitable that you'd get a little mad and maybe snap?
Why does it sound like she's trying to justify what happened?
She's sticking up for a parent who isn't a parent.
A parent who would hit his daughter.
She's my friend, but with the way she's acting right now...
as her friend
Scene no. 373
I find her revolting.
"It was inevitable that he'd hit you"?
What the hell are you talking about?!
Should you really be saying that? Isn't that what you should find most unforgivable—
Isn't it okay, just this once?
You promised, didn't you, Araragi-kun?
You promised, didn't you, Araragi-kun?!
You promised not to tell anyone, didn't you?
But that's not...
But that's not a promise I can keep—
Please, Araragi-kun!
Don't tell anyone about this.
Hanekawa...
But I...
Please don't tell anyone.
If you keep this a secret, I'll do anything you want!
What? For real?! You'll do anything?!
Hell yeah!
A-Araragi-kun?
Oh man, what should I do?
H—
What should I have her do? What should I have her do?!
What'd be the best thing I could have her do?
Hu—
No!
Wait, hold on! Don't panic!
Hu—
Don't get too worked up! This is the time to be calm and collected!
Stay dignified!
Hu—
I have to make the most of this unprecedented opportunity!
H-Huh?
Is that how you react?
Is this supposed to be that kind of scene?
Isn't it one where you're touched by my sincerity and reluctantly swear eternal silence?
Sincerity? The heck is that? I have no idea!
Ms Tsubasa will do whatever you demand of her, Araragi.
Scene no. 412
Anything, eh?
Who's that Ms. Tsubasa?
Scene no. 413
Man, I really don't know what I should pick.
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
Scene no. 414
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
Scene no. 414
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
Scene no. 414
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
Scene no. 414
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
Scene no. 414
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
Scene no. 414
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
Scene no. 414
Shit! My indecisiveness is starting to piss me off.
Come on! It's at times like these where making a prompt decision makes you a man among men.
No, it'd make you the worst kind of man.
Hey, Araragi-kun. Do you remember that serious and heavy topic we were discussing just a minute ago?
I don't.
You don't, huh?
Araragi? Who's that supposed to be?
So you even forgot your own name.
She'll do anything, eh?
But really, what on earth should I have her do?
There are so many options that it's impossible to choose!
Actually wait, this is more like a short essay!
My composition skills are being put to the test!
Hold on!
Come to think of it, Hanekawa hasn't placed any restrictions on the number of wishes she'll grant me.
So her words, depending on how you take them,
might just mean she's willing to forever do as I say!
Just one!
I'll do whatever you want me to, but only once.
Damn, I let her add that clause.
I'm starting to get a headache here, seriously.
For the time being, Hanekawa,
let's head to a more secluded place.
All right, fine. I understand.
Not like I have anywhere else to be.
I took Hanekawa to some nearby bushes.
What's with you, Araragi-kun?
You're really beating around the bush here.
Or maybe it's because you can't think of anything?
Or maybe, perhaps, what you want to do is stare a hole through me like you are right now?
What do they call it... ogling?
Hanekawa.
What?
That's not what I want to do.
I...
What I want to do is lick the heck out of the bruise that's under that bandage!
And in spite of that we
laugh knowingly as though we
planned it beforehand
Sigh if you want to
and take a deep breath then
Don't worry if it looks foolish
I will keep waiting
for what you wish for
Would it be a lie to say
that there is still time?
I don't want to be saved
I don't want to be rewarded
I just want to enjoy these fragile days
Every day I make my wishes
My experiences remain bittersweet
Far atop the horizon I felt
my fading daydream
Scene no. 456
As I still have lingering side-effects from when I was a vampire,
my blood and saliva have healing abilities.
I'll mention, just in case, that as a scaredy-cat who didn't have the balls to lick Hanekawa's face,
I instead pricked my fingertip with a safety pin and applied my blood to her bruise.
It was a perfectly wholesome act.
Thank you.
Put that bandage back on, just in case.
It's weird for a bruise to just disappear.
You think my parents would catch on?
They wouldn't.
They're not the kind of people who would.
I could chop my hair off, but I don't think they'd notice that I did.
They probably don't even remember my face.
Oh, hey.
That was quick!
Don't just ignore me like that.
At least tell your cute little sister that you're home.
Are you done shopping?
Shopping?
No, the shopping...
went undone.
Forget dealing with my pent up frustration, I've only ended up getting more depressed.
These feelings and desires only continue to...
bury me under their weight.
Preview
Script: Nisio Isin
Illustrations: Haritama Hiroki
This is a preview hallucination.
Preview
The talk of the town,
even on New Year's Eve...
Will be us!
The Fire Sisters!
There exists an animal called the Tardigrade.
Preview
We'd better hurry,
or else we'll be
late for the New Year's
Eve broadcast!
It is said to be immortal by some, due to its ability to enter a state not of hibernation, but of anhydrobiosis.
Preview
Roll Roll
Sisters of mine!
Use this!
Thanks, Bro!
Cryptobiosis, in other words.
It's an animal that can survive the harshest of conditions, but it also has a weakness.
Preview
This way!
Ah!     Hanekawa!
It dies if it's crushed.
Preview
Flip!
It's actually that way!
Thank you!
What are you, a vampire?
Next Episode: Tsubasa Family Part Two.
Preview
Next Episode
Tsubasa  Family      Part  Two
All living things are family.
Preview
We were tricked!
We couldn't make
it in time!