Let's recall the events of that ominous Golden Week that I spent flirting with Hanekawa Tsubasa to my heart's content.
They are bitter memories, they are sour memories, but somewhere deep down there's sweetness to be found.
Let's recall the events of those nine golden days, events that I want to forget if possible,
and even if not, I want to undo them.
Timewise, it was during the two weeks of my spring break between my second and third years in high school,
during the month I experienced hell itself; it was such a time.
She was bewitched by a cat.
A cat.
A felid, a carnivore, a mammal.
Ever since, I can't stand cats.
I'm afraid of cats.
Yes, just as I'm afraid of Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Now please let me tell you about a dream I saw last night.
29th April, Saturday, morning
Araragi
Tsubasa Family     Part One
Kneel
Colored artwork
Hate                                                            Neutral                                                            Love
Sit up straight
HỒI          TƯỞNG
H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san  H-san
Yaharu Bookstore
Law
Qualifications, Jobs
Nutritious recipes
How to cook for someone ill
Recipes
and western-style sweets
Japanese Literature
Floor guide for the 1st floor
Kobe
Chugoku
Shikoku
Kyushu
Okinawa
Then His-Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness said to the old man: "If this be thy daughter, wilt thou offer her to me?" He replied, saying: "With reverence, but I know not thy august name." Then be replied, saying: "I am elder brother to the Heaven-Shining-Great-August deity. So I hath now descended from Heaven." Then the deities Foot-Stroking-Elder and Hand-Stroking-Elder said: "If that be so, with reverence will we offer her to thee." So His-Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness, at once taking and changing, the young girl into a multitudinous and close-toothed comb which he stuck into his august hair-bunch, said to the deities Foot-Stroking-Elder and Hand-Stroking-Elder: "Do you distill some eightfold refined liquor? Also make a fence round about, in that fence make eight gates, at each gate tie together eight platforms, on each platform put a liquor-vat, and into each vat pour the eightfold refined liquor, and wait." So as they waited after having thus prepared everything in accordance with his bidding the eight-forked serpent came truly as the old man had said, and immediately dipped a head into each vat, and drank the liquor. Thereupon it was intoxicated with drinking, and all the heads lay down and slept. Then His-Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness drew the ten-grasp saber that was augustly girded on him, and cut the serpent in pieces, so that the River Hi flowed on changed into a river of blood. So when he cut the middle tail, the edge of his august sword broke. Then, thinking it strange, he thrust into and split the flesh with the point of his august sword and looked, and there was a great sword within. So he took this great sword, and, thinking it a strange thing, he respectfully informed the Heaven-Shining-Great-August deity. This was the Herb-Quelling Great Sword. So thereupon His Swift-Impetuous-Male-Augustness sought in the land of Idzumo for a place where he might build a palace. Then he arrived at a place called Suga, and said: "On coming to this place my august heart is pure," and in that place he built a palace to dwell in. So that place is now called Suga. When this great deity, first built the palace of Suga, clouds rose up thence. Then he made an august song. That song said: "Eight clouds arise. The eightfold fence of Idzumo makes an eightfold fence for the spouses to retire within. Oh, that eightfold fence." Then he called the Deity Foot-Stroking-Elder and said: "Thee do I appoint Headman of my palace," and moreover bestowed on him the name of Master-of-the-Temple-of-Inada-Eight-Eared-Deity-of-Suga. And again, having wedded the Divine-Princess-of-Great-Majesty, daughter of the Deity Great-Mountain-Possessor, he begot children: the Great-Harvest Deity and the August-Spirit-of-Food. The elder brother, the Deity Eight-Island-Ruler wedded Princess-Falling-Like-the-Flowers-of-the-Trees, daughter of the Deity Great-Mountain-Possessor, and
Kneel
Rōsokuzawa
Somehow
Go  all  the  way!
Yaybe!
Yaybe......
Gratitude
Normal
Nope
Sit up straight
What I'm saying is, H-san has breasts appealing enough to
Nope
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Without a word.
Without any expression.
Without thinking, I touched her without any further ado.
Not  a  touch  but  a  catch
Breast
warning
Ah, geez. You went too far fondling your sister's breasts there!
Tsukihi: "It was good, wasn't it?"
Koyomi: "It wasn't bad."
That's right.
I guess I was lucky I realized the truth after a single touch
That's the conclusion?
Taxi
Failure
as her friend
Ms Tsubasa will do whatever you demand of her, Araragi.
Who's that Ms. Tsubasa?
I was considering asking her to pretend
to be a teacher, and I accidentally said it.
The talk of the town,
even on New Year's Eve...
Will be us!
The Fire Sisters!
We'd better hurry,
or else we'll be
late for the New Year's
Eve broadcast!
Roll Roll
Sisters of mine!
Use this!
Thanks, Bro!
This way!
Ah!     Hanekawa!
Flip!
It's actually that way!
Thank you!
We were tricked!
We couldn't make
it in time!